Guide to the Skizzenbuch: collection of drawings done for Junkers Flugzeug- und Motorenwerke AG, Dessau, 1941-1943
Department of Special Collections
Skizzenbuch: collection of drawings done for Junkers Flugzeug- und Motorenwerke AG, Dessau,
1941-1943
Special Collections M0795
Liska, Hans, 1907-
1.25 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Hubert Wegner, 1994
Scope and Content
Includes teaching materials for artists hired by Junkers to draw war events. These documents come, for the most part, from the archives of Johannes Lebek. All the teaching materials for the engine-builders were given by Katharina Michel.
Access terms
Junkers Flugzeug- und- Motorenwerke AG, Dessau; Aircraft Industry--Germany; Science-- History; Artists-- Germany; Sketches; Woodblocks
Container List
- Copies of 4 woodcuts from the time of the Junkers
  - Assembly of airplanes' engines, 1943, WV211
  - On the test stand, 1943, WV211f
  - In the foundry, 1943, WV212
  - In the forge, 1943, WV213
- Copies of 2 drawings
  - Junker's forging hammer
  - Junker's propeller-copy machine
- Teaching material CC1, E1 to E3, and S1 to S4, 8 sheets
- Liska's sketch-notebook, Junkers Flugzeug-u. Motorenwerke AG, 34 sheets
- Teaching guide "Reading of drawings for engine-builders", by Ministry of Aviation (Reichsluftfahrtministerium)
- Teaching guide of representative of MInistry of aviation for the aviation industry personnel.
- Teaching material for training of assemblers of control systems for plane engine Jumo 211 1941, January
- Teaching material for trainers of assemblers "Maintenance practice" on Jumo 211 1941, August
- Lebek, Johannes, 1901 - 1985
- Junkers Flugzeug- und- Motorenwerke AG, Dessau.